fooducate.com 2013-05-09

# Fooducate | Privacy Policy

_Last Updated:_ April 15, 2012 

Hello! Welcome to Fooducate, Ltd. ("we" "us" "our" or “Fooducate"). 

This is our privacy policy. 

Fooducate is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to the Fooducate Site, Apps, Content, APIs, and data feeds (collectively the "Services”) and governs data collection and usage. By using the Services, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. 

By submitting personally identifiable information (“PII”) through our Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your PII in accordance with our Privacy Policy. 

## COLLECTION AND USE OF YOUR INFORMATION

**Activity and log data.** We automatically store information related to your use of the Services, such as the pages you view on the Site, your browser type, IP address, requested URL, referring URL, and the date and time of your visit. We also log the products you scan, view, and other actions you perform while using the Services. We use this type of information to administer the Services and provide the highest possible level of service to you. We also use this information in the aggregate to perform statistical analyses of user behavior and characteristics in order to measure interest in and use of the various areas of the Services. 

**Email.** If you register to the Services or contact us via e-mail, we will collect your name and e-mail address, as well as any other content included in the e-mail, in order to send you a reply. When you post messages or comments on the bulletin board, chat room, blog or forum of our Services, the information contained in your posting will be stored on our service provider’s servers. 

**Collection by Third Parties.** If you post content (“Public Content”) for public view on the Services, we may distribute such Public Content to a wider audience by sharing it (or portions of it) with third parties so that they can publish it on their own websites and media platforms. We may ask them to credit you as the source of these contributions by including your account name and profile photo. We allow you to access third party services, such as Facebook and Twitter, to share your selected Public Content with those services. You can always opt out in your Fooducate account settings. 

**Third party advertising.** Third parties serve some of the ads across our Services. We do not send any individualized personal information to them, but they may have access to information that they obtain through cookies or that you share with them yourself. Note that we do not rent, share, sell or trade PII with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. 

The content posted by these third parties will be reasonably identifiable as coming from a third party. We do not provide any PII to these advertisers, third-party websites, or other businesses, although on occasion we may mutually share non-personally identifiable (e.g., demographic) information to facilitate delivery of relevant advertisements. These third-party websites, businesses, and advertisers, or advertising companies working on their behalf, sometimes use tracking technology to deliver (or "serve") the advertisements that appear on our Services directly to your browser or app. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (also known as action tags or single-pixel gifs), and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize or optimize advertising content. We do not have access to or control over cookies or other technologies that they may use, and the information practices of these advertisers and third-party websites or businesses are not covered by this Policy but are covered by their respective privacy policies. Some, but not all, third party advertising companies provide a mechanism to opt-out of their technology. 

**Cookies.** A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes such as site visitation. We send cookies to your computer in order to uniquely identify your browser and improve the quality of our service. We may use both session cookies (which expire once you close your browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them). Persistent cookies can be removed by following your browser help file directions. If you choose to disable cookies, some areas of the Site may not work properly or at all. Our cookies are linked to your information, such as your nickname, email address and password. We enable some of our business partners to use cookies in conjunction with your use of the Site (for example Google Analytics). We have no access to or control over the use of these cookies. These cookies collect information about your use of the Site, such as which web site you came from, which pages you visited within the Site, and possibly other sites you visit if those sites cooperate with the same third party, but do not collect your name, email address, contact information or other personally identifiable information that by itself would allow the third party to identify or contact you. 

**Pixel Tags.** In our emails to you, we may use "pixel tags", commonly referred to as web beacons to determine if your email software or service can display html-formatted email (this helps us optimize the size of our email messages and conserve bandwidth). 

Feedback. You should feel free to give us feedback, register a complaint, or ask questions about the Services. We may store your communications, including any personal information you include in them, so that we can effectively respond to you. 

**Administration.** We may use the information described above for routine administrative purposes, such as investigating abuses on the Site, responding to user inquiries and enforcing and applying our Terms of Service and Statement. 

## ADDITIONAL MATTERS

**Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable).** We share aggregated demographic and usage information about users of the Services with our business partners, such as food manufacturers, and retail stores. This information does not identify individual users. We do not link aggregate user data with PII. 

**Legal Disclaimer.** We reserve the right to disclose your PII as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights (or those of our Services users) and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Services. 

**Affiliates.** Although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, "Affiliates"), we may in the future. We may share some or all of your PII with these Affiliates, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. If another company acquires our company or our assets, that company will possess the PII collected by it and us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your PII as described in this Privacy Policy. 

**Disclosure to Third Party Service Providers.** We may share your PII with our third party service providers to provide you with the Services. Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, these third party service providers are required not to use your PII other than to provide the services requested by us. You expressly consent to the sharing of your PII with our service providers for the sole purpose of providing services to you. 

**Marketing.** We do not share your PII with third parties for promotional purposes unless you have opted-in to such disclosure. If you have opted-in to have your PII shared, to opt-out from receiving further communications from any third party that is not our agent or service provider, please contact that marketing partner/affiliate directly. 

**Links To Other Websites.** If you click on a link to a third party site, you will leave the Services and go to the site you selected. Because we cannot control the activities of third parties, we cannot accept responsibility for any use of your PII by such third parties, and we cannot guarantee that they will adhere to the same privacy practices as Fooducate. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policies of any other service provider from whom you request services. 

**Bulletin Boards/Chat Rooms/Blogs/Forums.** If you use a bulletin board, chat room, blog or forum on the Services, you should be aware that any PII you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the PII you choose to submit in these forums. 

**Social Media (Features) and Widgets.** Our Services includes Social Media Features (“Social Media Features”), such as the Facebook Like button and the Pinterest Pin button. The Social Media Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site and Services, and may set a cookie to enable the Social Media Features to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

## COMMUNICATIONS FROM THE SITE

**Service-related Announcements.** We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. 

**Customer Service.** Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. 

**Updating Personally Identifiable Information.** If your personally identifiable information changes, you may update it by making the changes in the Fooducate Services Settings screen. If you wish to delete your account please email us at [support@Fooducate.com](mailto:support@Fooducate.com). We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. 

## DATA RETENTION

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [support@Fooducate.com](mailto:support@Fooducate.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

## SECURITY

The security of your PII is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is perfectly secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your PII, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

## CHANGES IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY

If we decide to change our privacy practices, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy, the home page our Site, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we change how we use your personally identifiable information, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. 

## QUESTIONS

Any questions about this Privacy Policy should be addressed to privacy@Fooducate.com
